<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Perl | Steven's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://isunix.github.io/blog/categories/perl/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://isunix.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-31T17:59:46+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://isunix.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steven Sun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Something About Intermediate Perl]]></title>
    <link href="http://isunix.github.io/blog/2014/05/31/something-about-intermediate-perl/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-31T17:22:45+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://isunix.github.io/blog/2014/05/31/something-about-intermediate-perl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know the language of Perl in late 2011 or early 2012 when I graduated from colleage. I used to spend a lot of time on it when I was in the first company I joined, since that company uses a lot of Perl to do system administratiion. The problem is I have not used perl to write any useful scripts, although I have crafted some small snipptes.</p>

<p>I always think Perl is not a beautiful language. I know something about Python also, I have spent quite a while to learn Ruby and currently I am using PHP to write some internal tools for my team. I have no idea why deep down in my heart I want to write something useful in Perl. Maybe because it is hard(Kennedy, haha).!!!</p>

<p>I choose the book &ldquo;intermediate Perl&rdquo; here, because it is the first book on Perl that I bought. I did not buy learning Perl first because I thought I can grasp the basic of Perl just by reading the ebook and there is no need to buy the elementary one. The fact is I bought &ldquo;learning Perl&rdquo; several months later. I read &ldquo;intermediate Perl&rdquo; several times, but I can not claim that I can understand it all, actually if I grasp the contents in that book, now it will not be necessary for me to write this post any more. So this post will be the start of a series of topics releated to Perl. Of course I will open another series to write some of the skills that may be useful for a new comer to Perl. I will translate this book into Chinese only for my own study.</p>

<p>That is it, let us embark on a new journey!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
